ms.gov 2010-06-23

# Privacy Policy | The Official State Web Site of Mississippi

Thank you for visiting Mississippi.gov and reviewing our Privacy Notice. This notice addresses collection, use, security of, and access to information that may be obtained through your use of the Mississippi.gov Portal. You understand and agree that in addition to this Mississippi.gov Privacy Notice, each state agency or institution website you visit may have a unique Privacy Notice. This notice covers the following topics:

  * Information Collected and How it is Used
  * Personal Information and Choice
  * Public Disclosure
  * Access and Correction of Personal Information
  * Cookies
  * Security
  * Disclaimer
  * Contact Information

If you do nothing during your visit to Mississippi.gov but browse or download information, we automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:

  1. The Internet Protocol Address and domain name used but not the email address. The Internet Protocol address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. The Internet Protocol Address is used to direct Internet traffic to you.
  2. The type of browser and operating system you used
  3. The date and time you visited this site
  4. The web pages or services you accessed at this site
  5. The web site you visited prior to coming to this web site

The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us.

We use your email address to respond appropriately. This may be to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to further improve our web site, or to forward the email to another agency for appropriate action.

"Personally Identifiable Information" is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personally Identifiable Information includes, but is not limited to, such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information.

We collect no Personally Identifiable Information about you unless you voluntarily participate in an activity that asks for information (i.e. sending an email, accessing a fee-based service etc.). If you choose not to participate in these activities, your choice will in no way affect your ability to use any other functions of Mississippi.gov.

If Personally Identifiable Information is requested on the web site or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.

A special note about children: Children should only use our fee-based services with their parent or guardian's verifiable permission and/or supervision.

In accordance with the laws of the State of Mississippi, Mississippi.gov will ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by the state. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals. Both state and federal laws provide exceptions.

All information collected at this site becomes public records that may be subject to inspection and copying by the public, unless an exemption in law exists.

Each agency, in accordance with published rules, shall make available for public inspection and copying all public records unless the record falls within the specific exemptions. See Section 25-61-1 and following of the Mississippi Code Annotated for the Mississippi Public Records Act.

In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and the Public Records Act or other law governing the disclosure of records, the Public Records Act or other applicable law will control.

You can review any personal information we collect about you. You may recommend changes to your personal information you believe in error by submitting a written request that credibly shows the error. If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact us. In all cases, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. See Contact Information section.

To better serve users many web sites use "cookies" to customize your browsing experience. Cookies are simple text files stored on your computer by your web browser. These files identify you as a unique user and track your movements through the site. This technology allows us to verify your transaction requests and walk you through some of the functions on the portal.

Mississippi.gov uses cookies. These cookies are temporary in nature and expire at the end of a session. If your browser has cookies disabled, information will be provided to you on how to enable your browser to accept cookies.

The State of Mississippi Department of Information Technology Services (ITS), as manager of Mississippi.gov, has taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its telecommunications and computing infrastructure, including but not limited to authentication, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. Security measures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day practices of the entire portal operating environment. One of the key features is the use of SSL (Secure Socket Layer) for transmission of confidential information.

This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided at Mississippi.gov.

Mississippi.gov could provide links to other web sites. These include links to web sites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations, and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on Mississippi.gov and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another web site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.

To access your Personally Identifiable Information we collect, if any, or to request correction of factual errors in your Personally Identifiable Information or should you need further information on our Privacy Policy, please contact us

| By mail at | MS Dept. of Information Technology Services  
ATTN: Portal  
301 North Lamar, Suite 508  
Jackson, MS 39201-1495  
---|---  
By telephone at | TOLL FREE: (866) MS1-EGOV (866) 671-3468  
LOCAL (601) 359-EGOV (601) 359-3468  
By e-mail at | Contact Us  
By fax at | (601) 576-EGOV (601) 576-3468
